Accessibility

* [C](javascript:sessionadd('day'))
* [C](javascript:sessionadd('noon'))
* [C](javascript:sessionadd('night'))
* [A](javascript:fontadd('small'))
* [A](javascript:fontadd('medium'))
* [A](javascript:fontadd('large'))

KAZ Type Data Protection, Security, and Privacy Policy
======================================================

Last updated: July 19, 2023

Statement:

KAZ Type is committed to data security and the fair and transparent processing of personal information. As our customer, you will find that we are secure, reliable, and discreet.

What does this Data Protection, Security, and Privacy Policy cover?

Our Data Protection, Security and Privacy Policy explains what, how, and why we collect personal data. It further explains how we store data, who we share it with, and your rights concerning the personal data you provide. It also includes KAZ Type's advertising and marketing procedures.

This data Protection, Security, and Privacy Policy applies to all the personal data we collect if you visit our website or use our products and services. It complies with current data protection laws, particularly the Data Protection Act 2018 and the UK General Data Protection Regulation (UK GDPR), May 2018.

**Note:** ‘Websites’ include online applications and web-based services. In this policy, we refer to desktop and online applications as ‘apps’.

Who is KAZ Type?

KAZ Type is an education software company offering a range of online and downloadable touch typing courses and regulated assessments.

KAZ Type is a Company Limited by Guarantee (Registered No. 09504896).

Our registered address is KAZ Type, Village Farm, Village Street, Royal Leamington Spa, Warwickshire, CV33 9AP UK.

We are registered as a ‘data controller’ with the Information Commissioner’s Office - ICO (please view the certificate on our website) concerning processing any personal data you provide to us when you visit our website or use our products and services.

We follow the guidelines as published by ICO.org.uk. For further information: [ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection.](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/).

Visitors to our website - Collecting browsing information

When you visit the KAZ website, we anonymously collect information your browser or device sends to our server using cookies or similar technologies.

What is a ‘cookie’?

A ‘cookie’ is a small text file placed on your computer or device by our web page. They are frequently used to collect standard internet log information, including IP address, track visitor use of the website, and compile statistical reports on website activity. Cookies are also used to help us improve our website and tailor it to customer needs. A cookie can later be retrieved by our web page server.

Data we collect using cookies is only processed in a way that does not personally identify anyone and does not give us access to your computer.

You can decline or choose how a cookie will be accepted by modifying your preferences and options in your internet browser. You may still be able to use some information-only pages even if you do not accept cookies.

KAZ Type does not store any personal information in a cookie. However, if we want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be upfront about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

Cookies are used by the web server to store information in Session Variables. Session variables reside on the web server for a short period of time (about 20 minutes). Accordingly, some KAZ Type website and online course features require that you accept cookies.

We also use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information to understand better how visitors use the KAZ website. This includes analysing date, time, visitor numbers, page visits, and any information downloaded, all of which are processed in a way that does not identify the individual.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, you can visit tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

Our website may contain links to other websites. When you link to these sites, you leave our website, and your communications are no longer protected by our privacy notice. KAZ Type is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these websites. We recommend that you review the privacy notice of those sites to fully understand what information is collected and how it is used.

When does KAZ Type collect personal data?

The information we collect about you depends on how you use the facilities we offer.

We collect and process personal data to identify you and better serve you. Some of this information may be optional. Data is collected when you:

Visit our website (through the use of cookies).

Complete a form through our website (e.g., support, general enquiries or ‘free trial’).

Enter into a contract with us, or apply to become an affiliate or an approved sub-centre.

Sign-up to receive communications (e.g., newsletters, events). However, you can unsubscribe to receive these communications anytime by emailing [support@kaz-type.com](https://kaz-type.com/support@kaz-type.com) or clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link.

Correspond with us by phone, in writing, or by email.

We will preserve the content of any email you send us if we believe we have a legal requirement to do so. Our employees will monitor your email content for security issues, including where email abuse is suspected. Our response to you will be monitored for quality assurance issues.

Attend a KAZ Type event, including online events (e.g., webinars, training).

Register and purchase a course or assessment, submitting associated documentation and bank details.

We utilise the facilities of ‘Trust Payments’ – a secure data information company that takes payment from customers on behalf of KAZ Type.

**Note:** KAZ Type do not receive or hold any card payment information on our servers.

When you purchase or activate an app, we collect information about your app – (license key and device). When updating, certain apps communicate automatically with our servers to see if you have a valid license and are eligible for the update.

Register and upload learner data for online courses or assessments through our secure platform.

Once a licence expires, or a school or enterprise notifies us of ’non-renewal', we allow the licence to expire naturally, and once expired, all data contained within that license is deleted. When data is deleted from the system, it is wiped completely from our secure server. Data is never converted to hard copy.

Why does KAZ Type collect and process personal data?

We collect and process personal data solely to exercise our legitimate business functions and meet our responsibilities, both statutory and otherwise. This includes using your personal details to provide the products and services you have requested; communications in relation to these products and services, including issues, complaints, and disputes; administrative support; performing analytical processes to support our business functions; and reporting to our regulators.

What personal data does KAZ Type collect and process?

**1\. For Schools, Colleges, Universities & Businesses** – Mainstream and Neurodiverse Touch Typing Courses

Administrators:

Full name, establishment address, email address, job title, and course details.

Learners:

Data includes personal information for the purpose of registering learners:

Full name and email address (real or pseudo).

Children’s Privacy:

**The safety and protection of children while using our online courses and their data privacy is paramount to us. We do not allow advertisements, solicitation by email, or share learner data with any third party.**

We, KAZ Type, do not knowingly register or collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the minimum required ages specified herein. Residents of the EU must be at least 16 years of age. Persons outside of the EU must be at least 13 years of age. Persons who are under 16 must obtain parental consent to use our services. KAZ Type allows parents, IT administrators, and teachers to provide consent on behalf of parents for students to use our services. IT administrators and teachers are responsible for informing parents or legal guardians about the use of our services, in particular, if the student is below the minimum required age. If you learn that a child has provided us with personal information in violation of this Privacy Policy, you can alert us at [support@kaz-type.com](#).

Additional information for US Schools: 

Children may use KAZ Type software provided the school has complied with its responsibilities under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (‘FERPA’) and Children's Internet Protection Act for K-12 Schools (‘CIPA’).

If a teacher or school official has consented to our collection of information from children who are students in a manner consistent with CIPA, we will collect and use such personal information solely for the use and benefit of the school and for no other commercial purpose. As such, we do not send promotional material or surveys to children using KAZ Type’s software. A school or district must obtain the consent of a parent or legal guardian before providing KAZ Type with any child’s personal information.

The Student Online Personal Protection Act, or SOPPA, is the data privacy law that regulates student data collection and use by schools, the Illinois State Board of Education, and education technology (EdTech) vendors

Student Online Personal Protection Act (SOPPA): Guarantees that student data is protected when collected by educational technology companies, and that data is used for beneficial purposes only.

Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA): Restricts the collection of personal information from children under 13 by companies operating websites, games, mobile applications, and digital services that are directed to children or that collect personal information from individuals known to be children.

Children’s Internet Protection Act (CIPA): Imposes certain requirements on schools that utilize the federal E-Rate program to receive discounts for internet access and other technology services, or that receive federal grants for other technology expenses. Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA): Governs information in a student’s education record, restricting access and use of student information

Data Accessibility:

Concerning our ‘Mainstream and Neurodiverse Touch Typing Courses for Schools, Colleges, Universities & Businesses’,

KAZ Type does not share data with any third party. However, we support access to student personal information to parents and students for review and correction through schools, teachers, educational or business entities.

2\. For Individual/home purchases:

If registering in the shop -

Full name, address, telephone number and email address in regard to products purchased online.

Guest checkout -

Name and email address.

3\. For Open Awards/Ofqual regulated Qualifications Level 1 and 2 (as per examining body requirements):

Full name, date of birth, address, telephone number, email address, photo ID, specific learning difficulties (for access arrangements), unique learner number if available (optional ‘special categories’ - gender, ethnicity, religion).

Open Awards/Ofqual may collect, store and use the above ‘special categories’ of sensitive personal information for statistical purposes, but all data will be anonymised.

Individual purchases only:

We keep webcam footage recordings of candidate’s aged 16+ undertaking remote online assessments for identification purposes and for monitoring the learner for the duration of the assessment. However, this footage will only remain on KAZ Type’s secure server until verification of candidate ID has been completed and for a **maximum period of 14 days**, after which it will automatically delete form our servers. (Parents or legal guardians may be present in the room for candidates under the age of 16.)

4\. Duke of Edinburgh Award Courses:

Course Only:

Full name, date of birth, address, telephone number, email address, eDofE number, specific learning difficulties, and parental consent if required.

Course plus Open Awards/Ofqual regulated Qualifications

Full name, date of birth, address, telephone number, email address, eDofE number, photo ID, unique learner number if available, specific learning difficulties (optional - gender, ethnicity, religion) and parental consent if required.

Open Awards/Ofqual may collect, store and use the above ‘special categories’ of sensitive personal information, but all data will be anonymised.

Who does KAZ Type share personal data with?

Concerning all our courses except those mentioned specifically below (Ofqual regulated qualifications and the DofE awards), **KAZ Type do not share data with any third party**.

**ONLY concerning Ofqual regulated Level 1 and Level 2 qualifications and DofE Award courses:**

1\. Ofqual regulated Level 1 and Level 2 qualifications:

As part of our legitimate business functions and **ONLY** concerning our Ofqual regulated Level 1 and Level 2 touch typing qualifications, we share personal data with our partners, Open Awards. They, in turn, will share the information with:

Ofqual Regulatory Body and The Department for Education (including collection by RM Education on behalf of the Department of Education) – regulator

Quality Assurance Agency (QAA) – regulator

UCAS – regulator

Learning Records Service (LRS)

Higher Education Institutions

External contractors and partners who undertake work on behalf of Open Awards, e.g., Portico (database developers), Hague (certificate printers), and Colerind (assessment platform - data recorded on the Open Awards database, secure portal and online assessment system)

Unless otherwise stated, data is normally shared and processed as anonymised data. However, there may be situations, such as an investigation or complaint, when Open Awards is required to process or share individual personal details due to a legitimate business reason. In these instances, Open Awards will share only the details necessary to the case and will endeavour to maintain the security of this information.

Centres are encouraged to register learners with their Unique Learner Number (ULN). Any ULNs provided will be validated through a secure link with the Learner Records Service (LRS) during the initial registration. If any ULNs are invalid, we will notify the relevant centre using our secure portal, to advise them of the actions required to rectify the error.

Upon achievement of Qualifications and/or Qualification units, Open Awards are required to pass the achievement details of learners to The Learning Records Service, which will update learners’ Personal Learning Records (PLR). This is done through a secure link between Open Awards and LRS databases. The PLR is a source of information to support learners in their decision-making in relation to further study, employment, or skills development. We only send achievement data to the PLR, where a learner has a valid ULN.

2\. DofE Award courses:

As part of our legitimate business functions and ONLY concerning our DofE Award courses, we share personal data with our partners, DofE.

Where do KAZ Type store personal data?

Our server is maintained and fully managed by our service provider, TSO Host, based in the UK. However, all data is stored on our secure VPS server located in the US. The data facility is an SQL, which does not allow remote access. All our sites and information are password protected with authorised access only.

How does KAZ Type protect and store personal data?

KAZ Type is committed to protecting the rights and privacy of individuals and the protection of personal data from theft, loss, or destruction. We take all reasonable steps to ensure our staff are aware of their obligations in relation to the security and confidentiality of personal data and the lawful processing of any personal data shared with them.

The KAZ Type platform is accessible only to pre-approved users through a secure login provided by KAZ Type. Users are bound by the Terms and Conditions of use of the platform, which prohibits the sharing of passwords or accounts.

The security of personal information is vitally important to us. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we endeavour to use commercially acceptable means to protect personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Changes to our Data Protection, Security, and Privacy Policy:

KAZ Type recognises that privacy and data protection concerns may change and evolve. We reserve the right to make changes to this Data Protection, Security, and Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any changes to this policy, we will inform you via a banner on the home page of our website. Please periodically check to see if there are any changes to this policy [https://kaz-type.com](https://kaz-type.com/). Once read and understood, click the ‘Accept’ button if you are happy with the changes. If you don’t agree to any of the changes, please contact us, and on your request, we will delete your data from our system.

Successor Entities:

KAZ Type ensures that successor entities that may acquire part or all of the signatory's organisation in the future will comply and act in accordance with the Student Privacy Pledge principles or allow users a choice to send information to the future entity or have their data deleted.

How to contact us:

If you have any questions or concerns with regard to this policy or our use of your personal data, please contact us at: [support@kaz-type.com](#).

Our website uses cookies to enhance your online experience. For more information please see our [Privacy Policy](https://kaz-type.com/privacy)

Accept

#### Information

#### Connect with Us

#### Newsletter

\*Our tests and surveys have shown that the majority of users complete the A-Z keys section in 90 minutes. However, this is not guaranteed and some individuals may take longer. KAZ is structured so that the individual can work at their own pace. Allow an average of 4 hours plus practise time to complete the entire course covering the rest of the keyboard.  
  
\*\* Estimated User Numbers

Copyright KAZ Type Limited 2023. KAZ is a registered trade mark of KAZ Type Limited.

Developed by : [**STERNIC Pvt. Ltd.**](https://www.sternic.com/)
